hey tavasi so you're the outbound
manager here at our Las Vegas facility
I'm our manager so what I do what I do
let's start over
tomasi inbound manager Las Vegas
facility what does that mean what's your
role so what we do is we do the
day-to-day operations and receiving so
anything that comes in for trucks
basically receive it make sure it gets
its license plate number then it goes to
one of our Overstock locations whether
it becd from there it triggers
replanting that we replenish the product
a little bit of what else we do is load
balance as well so we send out you know
to our other facilities balance out our
inventory let's talk about the life
cycle let's talk about the process when
uh what we call an SP shipping plan
people call them purchase order so
purchase order is created by a customer
there's a date scheduled the inbound
team books an appointment for when it's
going to show up right then it shows up
at the dock
then your team gets involved right yes
so basically what would happen is we
have the shipping plans purchase orders
that come in they can hit our docs as
soon as they hit our docks we open these
purchase plans and then we basically go
from looking to seeing what product we
have how many we have back order
whatever the case may be for that
specific shipping plan we basically
receive the stock in make sure whether
it's allocated to RSP ERC whatever
receiving sturgising location that we
have and then from there we put into
Overstock it's a sellable locations so
that now it triggers and allocates
orders so that we can get it replenished
yeah so let's break it down let's go a
little slower so product shows up first
we make sure it's the right product
right yes phase one phase two the system
tells us how many we want to receive in
this building and how many we want to
cross talk to other building 100 right
yes so
um once we do that the inbound product
for the most part that goes to Overstock
right we don't take new product and put
it directly on the pickable shelves we
put them into sellable but unpickable
locations in the Overstock location
right that stop one yeah step one yeah
and then how do we know how does your
team know to take some of that stock
from the pallet racks and put it in the
pickable shelves so that will then
trigger a replenishment so you can you
can do it one of two ways once we get
the shipping plan we can look and see
what's back order and then from there we
can know like okay we're gonna move
these rsps RCS whatever they are
strictly straight into a pickable
location got it so if a PO shows up or
an SP shows up and you have a back order
for let's say 20 units instead of
putting in an Overstock and then waiting
for the replenishment report to tell you
to put it away there you'll just take 20
or maybe you'll take 40 because you know
you're gonna need more and put it
straight and pick a bowl and then take
the other ones and tag them to go up
into the dock into the Overstock
locations yep okay and then
um when you think about how to divide
your team right so you got receiving
load balance which is both load
balancing off of SPS that came in as
well as pulling from the shelves sales
you've got inventory control you got
replan right where you gotta stock uh
the the pickable shells for the pickers
how do you think about limited number of
people some days are busy how do you
manage that so basically what I'll do is
I'll just plan the day out like if I
know on our calendar we have a Google
Calendar which tells us what phrase we
got coming so I'll look at that and see
through the day through the week for the
month and just kind of play it by that
see what we have coming in how many
people I know I'm gonna have in
receiving to how many operator operators
I'm gonna have to put these into
Overstock locations so it all depends
because sometimes we can walk in our
punishments a lot or punishment might
not be a lot one day but we might have a
lot of receiving so it's kind of like
delegating everybody into those
different types of uh uh departments
like as you say in inbound where it's
like okay you're going to work on low
balance today when you get a truck out
to AB this Friday or whatever the case
may be so it's really just delegating uh
the employees in the inbound to make
sure that we have enough everywhere
right and how do you think about what
you want to do during first shift versus
the second trip so my my biggest goal
like when I get in is everything that we
got coming in I want to receive it I
want to make sure that it has a license
plate number whether or a staging
location and then we get it up and into
the wrecks just so that all the orders
whatever orders we have back orders can
allocate for those we get the replay and
get it all out the door because the the
main goal is to make sure that outbound
is moving so whatever we get in I want
to make sure we're proactively looking
at it like okay we got these back orders
we need to make sure that we put these
products out so that we can get the uh
the pickers to pick them and then we
just keep cycling it through yeah
normally if a Pickers say that they're
not pulling up orders we always say
that's probably yours it's probably
replaying yeah 100 so I literally uh so
we we have a thing here where it's like
I tell Brian all the time you know if
the papers are telling us we uh that we
don't we're not pulling the orders or
he's telling me that I know it's a
replant so the biggest thing for me is
to make sure that I always look at
anything that's coming in on SBS that we
have that and then as far as
replenishment goes we'll just try to
keep it under 10 to make sure that we're
you know we're cruising through it
constantly feeding the the outbound
machine 100 100 all right
um what is I know things don't always go
perfect right so what are the sort of
the biggest problems that you face uh in
your role biggest problem it might be
something might come in non-compliant
and it may as soon as they hit it's our
doc we might get some of it in and then
it's like it'll allocate the orders but
we still receive some other stuff but
some of those stuff might be
non-compliant sit in we got to wait to
make sure uh we're reaching out to the
customer to our Wham and getting that
situated and then those might sit for
maybe a day maybe a week we don't really
know so a lot of that is a little bit of
frustration because it's like when you
get something in you want to get it
going you want to get it off your dock
right so like my biggest goal is always
make sure the doctor's empty whatever's
on the dock is accounted for right okay
so you're sort of halfway through you
try to scan something doesn't scan or
it's damaged or it doesn't match the SP
right so then you got to pause right
yeah you got all this stock on the dock
the Wham is our warehouse account
manager you ask him or her to like hey
talk to the customer see what's going on
what's up tell me what to do and then
the product's still sitting on the dock
at that point right at what point do you
say it's been a while I need to get I
need this that lane I need this dock
space I'm going to move this somewhere
else tag it as non-compliant so I get my
doc space back so we basically got like
four Flex Zones uh next star receiving
area so that we put our non-compliant
there so whether it sits longer than I
give it two days if it's just longer
than two days on a dock I'm moving
straight over to our Flex Zones which
are in a lot of compliance zones then
I'm kind of relying on our receiving
team myself as well to make sure that
we're reaching out following up hey just
courtesy follow-up what's going on with
this just to make sure it doesn't sit in
that non-compliance zone longer than it
needs to what's your favorite feature in
ship Arrow
the hospital you know like when a picker
goes to a location they flag it so when
they flag it it's our job to go figure
out what's wrong with it so we'll go
there we'll visit we'll do two maybe a
few things we'll scan the product make
sure the product scans see we'll count
it make sure we'll either pick or flag
it because they cut a flag for a
numerous reason the barcode doesn't scan
it's not enough in the location maybe
need a replan that we didn't get to fast
enough so I think the hospital is good
because it proactively lets us know
keeps the team on the feet where they're
like okay we need to go for Action these
uh locations and make sure they become
peekable again because as you know if
you flag a hospital look or you flag the
location it becomes non-pickable right
so yeah no other Pickers get sent there
which means orders can wait if they're
that's the only place to product it yep
what have you learned recently that's
helped you do your job better it's
really a mission thing I think uh so low
balance is helped a lot I think uh I've
I spent more time with the load balance
team within the last month or two really
just diving in with that in the figure
around out like how can we get these low
balance from our dock straight to our
Overstock location or pickable locations
see them at the inbound load balance so
we get a truck from ABE and you want to
get that on the Shelf without anywhere
anywhere yeah so it's like you do have
your uh your pros and cons with it but
the biggest thing I think is like it
makes it so much easier just to
literally just scan from one point and
then scan right back into your pickable
location you know so it makes it a lot
easier for us to move the product like
we're not having to receive anything
really we're just really moments in our
system boom it goes to a pickable
location even though it's from one
building to another it's actually just
an inventory yep all right perfect so
it's been a year that you've been here
what's the evolution been like when I
first got here I'm gonna be really
honest with you when I got here
everybody was kind of working anywhere
there was no designated areas so when we
got here it was uh me and uh Ryan got
here it's really just delegating the
fact of making sure that we had this
approach where it was like we're going
to designate these areas for certain
things you know we're going to clean up
our dock we're gonna to put our shelving
up make sure these customers have their
inventory here certain places you know a
lot has changed I think the biggest
thing is like getting the inventory
corrected counting the cycle count in
the building our full audit
um and really just uh taking ownership
of our inventory I think that was the
thing that I was kind of you know
pulling teeth with that when I first got
here it was like trying to figure out
what did we have here in the building
and I to say a year from now until now
it's like we've came a long way I can
actually say like if I send someone to a
location I know so I know it's there you
know so good inventory visibility yeah
100 so what do you what do you want to
see improve from now until a year from
now
um honestly just start just continue to
build off of what we've got going here
uh I think the biggest thing is uh we're
making
strides in making room for everything so
we have a lot more customers are
planning to get in so I want to make
sure that we have the capacity to have
that like we're getting containers left
and right
um so really just building off of
keeping our inventory uh accurate and
then uh having that space to always keep
the customers bringing their product
here and if you can help train a new
person stepping into the the role of
inventory manager for the first time or
inbound manager for the first time what
would you tell them
I would tell them keep a level head and
you know continue to uh just work the
inventory never ends so you're not going
to get it all in one shot so it's
something that it's uh it's steady
evolving it's always something new so
just keep a level hand and just continue
to work at it and uh it's it's honestly
it's a it's really like a competition
really with yourself trying to make sure
that every day you're gonna find
something new every day things might not
go the way they did yesterday so just
keep a level and the buildings
definitely improved in the time you've
been here Brian's been here I think the
team solidified we've got some good
stability we've got some really good
team members and in the results show
thank you you're doing great thank you
appreciate it
[Music]
thank you